Irene Clemente Aracil

MULTIMEDIA AND FRONTEND ENGINEER

Q she/her

◎ 東京都 新宿区 西落合

% 080 5121 5988

irenecats

☐ ireneclemt@gmail.com

in irene-cle

EXPERIENCE

 ${f EMBENTION}$ AERONAUTICS COMPANY FOCUSED IN UAVS

Alicante, Spain

Software Engineer, Full time

Oct 2021 - Jun 2024

- Major role in the creation, development and maintenance of 12 apps in Java during a critical turning point in the company's transition to a new ecosystem.
- Reworking and fixing the Java **legacy code**. Creating and redesigning interfaces to improve the overall visual coherence and flow of the applications. Mentoring junior developers into the codebase.
- Managing sensitive user data. Creating, fixing, and migrating between XML schemas to ensure our users' saved data is secure while updating to the latest releases.
- Worked with TypeScript and Angular in our new web app Veronte
 Ops. Developed new cartographic tools used to visually design UAVs'
 flight plans, taking into account suggestions from users and
 corporate clients.
- Working closely with several multidisciplinary departments, such as firmware and avionics, in order to rapidly introduce new features and overcome deadlocks.

Software Engineer, Intern

Mar 2021 - Oct 2021

• Identify, debug and resolve UI/UX issues, focusing on functional, layout and design issues using Java, JavaFX and CSS.

EDUCATION

BACHELOR'S DEGREE IN MULTIMEDIA ENGINEERING

University of Alicante, Spain

2016 - 2021

This program combines Computer Science with concepts of Graphic Design, focusing on Web Development, UI/UX design, Computer Graphics engines and Game Development.



PROJECTS

3D IMMERSIVE VIRTUAL ITINERARY

Bachelor's Degree Thesis

202

The environment is based on the City of Arts and Sciences complex in Valencia, Spain. In it, the user can walk around and admire the other architectural structures while interacting with several points of information about the complex, all from their web browser or desktop.

GO! GO!! ROBOT BRAWL

Senior Year Project

2019 - 2020

Go! Go!! Robot Brawl is a cartoon styled fighting game developed entirely from scratch for PC by a team of 5. I led the design and development of the graphic engine and its shaders, using only **C++** and **Open GL**. It's publicly available on itch.io.

ABOUT ME

4 5th of August, 1998

Hi! I'm Irene, an engineer from Spain with over +3 years of experience working in this field.

I really enjoy the challenge of making exciting Figma designs a reality. Also, I have a great interest in building multi-platform GUIs to plot graphical data, such as web 3D tools and maps.

SKILLS AND TOOLS

JAVA / PYTHON / JAVAFX

REACT / NEXT.JS / ANGULAR / JAVASCRIPT / TYPESCRIPT

XML / HTML / CSS / TAILWIND / FIGMA

NODE / EXPRESS / FIREBASE

SQL / OOP / ECS

GIT / SMARTGIT / GITHUB DESKTOP / GITHUB ACTIONS

INTELLIJ / VSCODE

AGILE / PROJECT MANAGEMENT

Q ACHIEVEMENTS

HONOURS

University of Alicante

Highest grade in the major for 2 subjects: Computer Graphics and Statistics.



SPANISH Native ENGLISH Business

CATALAN Business